舰长日志，星历1513.1
Captain's log, stardate 1513.1.
我们正在行星M-113的环绕轨道上运行
Our position, orbiting planet M-113.
在进取号上
On board the Enterprise,
史波克暂时代为指挥
Mr. Spock, temporarily in command.
在这颗行星上
On the planet...
是早已灭绝的古老文明遗迹
...the ruins of an ancient and long-dead civilisation.
“进取号”星舰的外科医生麦考伊
Ship's surgeon McCoy and myself are now beaming down
和我一起被传送到该行星的表面
to the planet's surface.
我们的任务是
Our mission,
为考古学家罗伯特·克瑞特和他的妻子南茜
routine medical examination of archaeologist Robert Crater
进行常规体检
and his wife Nancy.
虽然是日常工作，但是南茜·克瑞特
Routine, but for the fact that Nancy Crater is that one woman
实际上是麦考伊的旧相好
in Dr. McCoy's past.
医生，我们是不是该摘些鲜花？
Shall we pick some flowers, doctor?
当一个男人拜访他的前女友时
When a man visits an old girlfriend,
对方常会期望这类东西
she usually expects something like that.
这就是你哄女人开心、掳获芳心的绝招？
Is that how you get girls to like you, by bribing them?
这附近看来没有人吧
Doesn't seem to be anybody around, does there?
他们会来的
Well, they'll be along.
你提前了10分钟把我们赶下来
You rushed us down ten minutes early.
克瑞特教授在吗？
Professor Crater?
教授？
Professor?
克瑞特太太？
Mrs. Crater?
紧张吗，麦考伊医生？
Nervous, Dr. McCoy?
嗯，是有那么一点
Yeah, a little bit, I guess.
我们已经有10年没有见过面了
Well, you see, we walked out of each other's lives ten years ago.
当时她嫁给了克瑞特教授
She married Crater, and for all I know,
我觉得她可能完全不记得我了
she may have forgotten me completely.
吉姆，我太蠢了
Of all the bonehead ideas, Jim.
我怎么会为了这些愚蠢的想法而烦恼了？
How do I let myself in for things like this?
- 伦纳德！ - 南茜！
- Leonard. - Nancy.
你好啊
Hello.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
让我好好看看你
Let me look at you.
你还是那么年轻
You haven't aged a day.
对了，这是进取号星舰的舰长詹姆士·寇克
Oh, this is Captain Jim Kirk of the Enterprise.
克瑞特太太，我有听说过你的事
Mrs. Crater. I've heard a great deal about you.
希望都是好名声
All good, I hope.
这是星舰船员达内尔
And Crewman Darnell.
你好, 夫人？
How do you do, ma'am?
怎么了，达内尔？
Something wrong, Darnell?
对不起，长官，但是如果我没弄错的话，夫人
Excuse me, sir, but, ma'am, if I didn't know better, I would swear
我发誓，你应该是被我留在了瑞格里星球乐园的那个姑娘
that you were somebody I left behind on Wrigley's Pleasure Planet.
太神奇了，你真的太像那个…
It's funny, you're exactly like a girl that--
闭嘴，达内尔！
A little less mouth, Darnell.
对不起，我不是有意要…
I'm sorry, sir, I didn't mean to...
我是说我当然知道这不可能
I mean, I know it's impossible, of course.
达内尔，到外面呆着好吗？
Why don't you step outside, Darnell.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
或许我也该去外面呆着
Maybe I'll step outside too.
怎么？
What?
让李子一个人给我体检么？
And let Plum examine me all alone?
- 李子？ - 李子
- Plum? - Plum.
年轻的时候，我给伦纳德起的小名
A nickname I gave Leonard when we were very young.
我会，我会等教授来，然后马上给你们俩体检
I'll... I'll wait for the professor, and I'll catch you both at once.
我最好去找鲍伯
I'd better go get Bob.
他一开始挖掘，就会达到废寝忘食的程度
Every time he starts digging, he forgets time, sleep, food, everything.
很快就回来
Be back in a minute.
这里非常热，不是吗？
It's quite warm here, isn't it?
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilisations,
勇踏前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：吴涵知，kmdangdangli，心痕依，madscientist
校对：Micezhang，xjCGI
第一季第一集
人类的陷阱
舰长日志，补充记录
Captain's log, additional entry.
由于是常规任务
since our mission was routine,
我们毫不迟疑地被传送到该行星上
we had beamed down to the planet without suspicion.
我们全都没意识到登陆小组的每一个队员
we were totally unaware that each member of the landing party
所看到的女人是不同的，不同的南茜·克瑞特
was seeing a different woman, a different Nancy Crater.
克瑞特教授，我是寇克舰长
Professor Crater, I'm Captain Kirk.
这是--
This is--
英勇的舰长和勇猛的医生
The heroic captain and the intrepid doctor
穿越星际空间来维护我们的健康
cross interstellar space to preserve our health.
你们的责任感强过头了
Your sense of duty is overwhelming.
现在，能否请你们回去
Now, will you please go back where you came from
并转告你们的上级，别再来烦我们了
and tell whoever issues your orders to leave me and my wife alone?
我们需要更多的盐来抵抗高温
We need additional salt against the heat.
除此之外，我们很好，谢谢
Aside from that, we're doing very well, thank you.
你们过的很好，我很高兴
I'm pleased to hear you're doing well,
但我需要证实这一点
but I'm required to confirm that fact.
毫无疑问，好医生
Doubtless, the good surgeon
总喜欢用神秘的仪器刺我们的身体
will enjoy prodding and poking us with his arcane machinery.
离开！我们不需要你
Go away, we don't want you.
现在你想要的并不重要
What you want is unimportant right now.
你要知道这是按规定要求的
What you will get is what is required by the book.
规定“所有外星球上的研究人员
Quote, "All research personnel on alien planets are required
每隔一年都必须由一艘星舰的医生
to have their health certified by a starship surgeon
进行常规体检”
at one-year intervals."
不管你喜欢与否，教授，我必须--
Like it or not, professor, as commander of the ship, I'm required--
向每个人炫耀你的金色徽章所代表的权力 你很喜欢这样不是吗？
To show your gold braid to everyone. You love it, don't you?
交给你了，李子，麦考伊医生
He's all yours, Plum. Dr. McCoy.
请坐下深呼吸
Sit down and breathe deeply, please.
他叫你麦考伊医生？
Did I hear you call him Dr. McCoy?
是的
You did.
麦考伊
McCoy.
我听南茜提起过一个叫麦考伊的医生
I've heard Nancy speak of a Dr. McCoy.
那就是我，她没跟你说我在这里吗？
Well, that's me. Didn't she mention I was here?
你？你见过南茜了？
You--? You've seen Nancy?
她出去找你了
She went out to get you.
你也见过她了？你一直和这位好医生在一起？
You've seen her too. You were with the good doctor.
是的，怎么了？
Yes, why?
没什么，只是让我很高兴
Nothing. It's just that it gives me great pleasure to know
她见到了老朋友并可以结交新朋友
that she's gotten to see an old friend and has a chance for some company.
和我不同，我喜欢孤独
It's different for me. I enjoy solitude.
但对于女性，你懂的
But for a woman... You understand, of course.
她确实一点都没有变老
Well, it certainly hasn't aged her.
她跟12年前一模一样
She looks exactly as I knew her 12 years ago.
太神奇了，吉姆！就像一个25岁的女孩
Amazing, Jim, like a girl of 25.
抱歉，真的很抱歉，舰长
Oh, sorry. I'm sorry, captain.
请坐，我真是太失礼了
Sit down. I seem to have forgotten my manners.
没事
It's quite all right.
我没开玩笑，吉姆
I'm not joking, Jim.
她一点都没有变老，就连一根白头发都没有
She hasn't aged a day. There's not a grey hair on her head.
她有白头发，老骨头（麦考伊的另一个昵称）
She's got some grey, Bones.
请恕我冒昧，教授，她是个美丽端庄的女人
Excuse me, professor. She's a handsome woman, yes,
但不像是25岁，不是吗？
but hardly 25.
医生，你用过去爱慕的眼光来看我的妻子
You've seen my wife with the eyes of your past attachment, doctor.
我确定当南茜让…
I'm sure when Nancy lets...
当你再见到她时，她应该不是那么年轻了
When you see her again, she'll be of a believable age.
再怎么说，她怎么看也不会超过30岁
Well, at any rate, she doesn't look a day over 30.
这就是真爱啊
Genuine affection.
我很高兴你依然爱着她
I'm glad you still feel it for her.
你叫伦纳德，对吧？
Leonard, isn't it?
- 她是个好女人 - 张开嘴
- She's a fine woman. - Open your mouth.
为什么，我以为那仪器能--
Why, I thought the machine was--
这台仪器几乎可以做任何事
The machine is capable of almost anything,
扁桃体的健康检查也是常规体检中的一部分
but I'll still put my trust in a healthy set of tonsils.
现在张开嘴
Now, open your mouth.
麦考伊！
McCoy.
他死了，吉姆
Dead, Jim.
真奇怪，他脸上到处都是红斑
It's strange, the red mottling all over his face.
- 这是怎么了？ - 你觉得怎么了？
- What happened? - What do you suppose happened?
你们传送了一个无知的船员
You beamed down a crewman who doesn't know better
- 吃了未经测试的植物 - 我刚失去了一名船员，克瑞特太太
- than to eat an untested plant. - I've just lost a crewman, Mrs. Crater.
我想知道到底发生了什么
I wanna know what happened.
我…
Well, I...
I...
慢慢说，南茜
Take it easy, Nancy.
把你看到的告诉我们就好
Just tell us what you know.
好吧，我刚才…
Well, I was just...
我找不到鲍勃，就回来了
I couldn't find Bob, and I was coming back.
途中，我遇到了你们的船员
I crossed to your crewman.
我想让他知道
I wanted him to know
他说的那些话并没有冒犯我
I wasn't offended by the things he'd said back there.
你们记得的
You remember.
然后我…
Then I...
我发现他手里有一棵博尔吉亚植物
I noticed he had a Borgia plant in his hand.
我还没来得及说，他就…
Before I could say anything, he'd...
他就咬了一口，倒下了
He'd taken a bite from it, and he fell.
他整个脸都扭曲了
His face all twisted.
伦纳德，你这样看着我是不信我吗
Leonard, you look at me like you don't believe me.
不不不不，不是这样
No. No, no, no, it's not that at all.
我在想其他的事情
It's something entirely different.
吉姆，我想我们可以晚点再进行体检
Jim, I suppose we could complete these examinations later.
我们不需要体检，你可以看到我们很健康
We don't need an examination, you can see that.
也许你应该带上你的人
Perhaps you'd better take your man and--
教授，我们清楚自己的职责
We're well aware of our next duties, professor.
我们明天再来为你们体检
We'll complete your examinations tomorrow.
传送室
Transporter Room.
舰长，这里是传送室
Transporter Room, captain.
锁定我们，三人传送上舰
Lock onto us. Three beaming up.
舰长，已锁定你们
Locked onto you, captain.
盐，你问他要盐片了吗？
Salt. You did ask him about more salt tablets?
我会处理好补给的事的，南茜
I'll take care of the provisioning, Nancy.
乌乎拉小姐，你上一次的子空间记录
Miss Uhura, your last subspace log
在频率栏中出现了一个错误
contained an error in the frequencies column.
史波克先生，有时我在想
Mr. Spock, sometimes I think
如果我再听到“频率”一词就会哭出来的
if I hear that word "frequency" once more, I'll cry.
哭？
Cry?
我只是想挑起话头
I was just trying to start a conversation.
好吧，因为作为一个通讯官
Well, since it is illogical
逻辑上不会讨厌“频率”一词
for a communications officer to resent the word "frequency,"
- 我不知道 - 不，你知道
- I have no answer. - No, you have an answer.
我是一个性情多变的女人
I'm an illogical woman,
并且正开始对通讯控制台感到厌倦
who's beginning to feel too much a part of that communications console.
为什么你不说我是一个有魅力的姑娘
Why don't you tell me I'm an attractive young lady.
或者问我是否曾经堕入爱河
Or ask me if I've ever been in love.
跟我说说在你的瓦肯星球上满月时分
Tell me how your planet Vulcan looks on a lazy evening
令人慵懒的夜晚是什么样子
when the moon is full.
乌乎拉小姐，瓦肯星球上没有月亮
Vulcan has no moon, Miss Uhura.
史波克先生，我并不惊讶
I'm not surprised, Mr. Spock.
传送室呼叫舰桥，登陆小组正在返回
Transporter Room to bridge. Landing party returning.
其中一人死亡
They report one death.
舰桥收到
Bridge, acknowledging.
难以置信
I don't believe it.
- 请解释一下 - 解释什么？
- Explain. - You explain.
有人死了而你只是坐在这里
That means that somebody is dead, and you just sit there.
死的可能是寇克舰长
It could be Captain Kirk.
他可是你最接近于朋友的人
He's the closest thing you have to a friend.
通讯官，我对此表示关心与否
Lieutenant, my demonstration of concern
并不能改变什么
will not change what has happened.
传送室人手充足
The Transporter Room is very well manned
如果他们需要援助，他们会呼叫我
and they will call me if they need my assistance.
- 她说那是博尔吉亚植物 - 我没听说过
- She called it a Borgia plant. - Something new to me.
舰桥呼叫医务室
Bridge to Dispensary.
请讲，史波克
Go ahead, Mr. Spock.
在图书馆的记录带中，博尔吉亚植物
Borgia plant listed in library record tapes
是一种基于碳族三号元素（锗）的植物 地球上的茄科植物类似
as Carbon Group III vegetation, similar to Earth nightshade family.
含生物碱毒素，化学结构在多数M级星球中常见
Alkaloid poison, chemical structure common to most Class-M planets.
至于他脸上奇怪的色斑
About the strange mottling on his facial skin surface,
还无法考证
there is no reference to this symptom.
那他并非食物中毒
Well, then this man wasn't poisoned.
史波克大副，请待命
Stand by, Mr. Spock.
她说看见他吃了
She said she saw him eat the plant.
她弄错了，我熟悉生物碱及其毒性
She's mistaken. I know alkaloid poison and what to look for.
他体内并无中毒迹象
There's not a trace of it in his body.
可他口中有微量的毒素
There were bits in his mouth.
吉姆，用不着你来教我
Jim, don't tell me my business.
他什么都没吃
He could not have swallowed any.
我的仪器查不出任何毒素
My instruments would have picked up any trace of it.
- 那好生生的一个人怎么死了？ - 冷静点，听我说
- Then what kills a healthy man--? - Now, I'll tell you something else.
他不可能死，他丝毫异样都没有
This man shouldn't be dead. I can't find anything wrong with him.
根据检查结果，他可以活着
According to all the tests, he should get up
从这儿走出去
and just walk away from here.
真搞不懂
I don't know.
得重新再查一遍，估计有什么被忽略了
I'll have the tests double-checked. My eyes may be tricking me.
可我发誓，吉姆，我一见到她
But I swear, Jim, when I first saw her,
她的样子和十年前一模一样
she looked just as I'd known her ten years ago.
也许当时是我情不自禁
Granted, at the moment, I may have been looking at her
依然觉得她如此动人
through a romantic haze.
医生，你的旧爱如何影响你的判断
How your lost love affects your vision, doctor,
对此我不感兴趣，我失去了一名部下
doesn't interest me. I've lost a man.
我要知道他怎么死的
I wanna know what killed him.
是，长官
Yes, sir.
舰长日志，星历1513.4
Captain's log, stardate 1513.4.
于M-113星球的环绕轨道
In orbit around planet M-113.
一名参与登陆的船员
One crewman, member of the landing party...
暴力性死亡，原因未知
...dead by violence. Cause unknown.
但已排除了食物中毒
But we are certain the cause of death was not poison.
舰长，有新消息
Message, captain.
来自科林斯Ⅳ号的星舰基地
Starship base on Corinth IV,
询问我们为何迟迟不到，长官
requesting explanation of our delay here, sir.
指挥官多明格斯急需一些生活用品
Space Commander Dominguez says we have supplies he urgently needs.
告诉何塞他要的辣椒马上到
Tell José he'll get his chilli peppers when we get there.
是我亲手挑选的墨西哥顶级红辣椒
Tell him they're prime Mexican reds. I handpicked them myself.
少吃几天是不会死的
He won't die if he goes a few more days without them.
- 明白了吗？ - 明白了，舰长
- Got it? - Got it, captain.
如何？
Well?
记录不会错
No mistake in our record tapes.
就是博尔吉亚植物，唯一致命属性是生物碱毒素
Borgia plant. Sole deadly property is alkaloid poison.
克瑞特教授夫妇呢？
And Professor Crater and wife?
情况正常
Check out perfectly.
他们在这呆了近五年
They arrived here nearly five years ago,
被各种飞船造访
visited by various vessels,
输送了大批文物和考古报告
made fairly heavy shipments out of artefacts and reports.
可去年的输送记录明显减少
However, there has been a marked drop in shipments during the last year.
医务室呼叫舰长
Dispensary to captain.
- 我是寇克 - 有新发现
- Kirk here. - we found something.
- 发现了什么？ - 见面再说
- What is it? - I'd rather not put it on the speaker.
真有意思
Fascinating.
差点被我们忽略
So improbable we almost didn't check it.
- 什么？ - 氯化钠
- What? - Sodium chloride.
一点儿都没剩
Not a trace of it.
他体内的盐分为零
This man has no salt in his body at all.
你作何解释，医生？
Can you explain that, doctor?
我解释不了
I can't.
只知道他体内该有的盐分都没了
Except what we normally carry in our bodies is gone from his.
是他暴毙的原因
He would die almost instantly.
怎么会这样？他没有受伤的痕迹
How? There's no mark on his body.
除了脸上那些红圈
Except the red rings on his face.
你说过那只是肤斑
You called that skin mottling.
我当时是这么说，长官
I thought it was, sir.
又是我的错
Another error on my part.
我没在数你的错，老骨头
I'm not counting them, Bones.
- 能接受我的道歉吗？ - 没事的
- Are you in the mood for an apology? - Forget it.
我当时被她迷住了
I probably was mooning over her.
我应该忠于职守
I should have been thinking about my job.
你一直都很棒
Perhaps you were.
南茜和克瑞特曾多次提过
Both Nancy and Crater went out of their way
他们需要一样东西
to mention one item they needed.
盐片
Salt tablets.
史波克大副
Mr. Spock,
准备一组登陆小分队
outfit a landing party.
我们得下去问几个问题
We're beaming down with some questions.
舰长，你除了骚扰我们
One might think that you had more important duties
还有更重要的使命
than harassing people, captain.
教授，相信我，我知道我们身负重任
I have, professor. Believe me, I have.
克瑞特夫人在哪？我也想和她谈谈
Where is Mrs. Crater? I want to talk to her too.
舰长，你不能想来就来
Captain, you can't just beam down here
威胁我们，干扰我们的工作
and bully us and interfere with our work.
她人在哪？我耐心有限
Mrs. Crater. I won't ask again.
估计她在挖掘区
Possibly at the other diggings.
- 我们不做军事记录 - 格林，找到她
- We don't keep military logs here. - Green, find her.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
- 史波克 - 待命
- Mr. Spock. - Standing by.
斯特尔贞，把植物样本拿给史波克
Sturgeon, transport a sample of the plant to Mr. Spock.
看看这是否真的是博尔吉亚植物
We'll check if it's actually the Borgia plant
还是其他不明生物，明白吗，史波克？
or something we don't understand. You got that, Mr. Spock?
- 已分析完毕 - 舰长…
- Complete analysis. - Captain...
鉴于这不争的事实
...considering the inescapable fact
你侵入了我的星球…
that you are a trespasser on my planet--
您的抱怨我记下了，先生
Your complaint is noted, sir.
你看…
Look...
我的手下死于非命，至今不知为何
...something we don't understand killed one of my men.
你们也许正身处危境
It could prove to be a danger to you and Mrs. Crater too.
我们在这儿都快五年了
We've been here for almost five years.
如果真有什么危险的话
If there were anything hostile here,
我们早就知道了，不是吗？
we would know about it, wouldn't we?
老骨头，和教授说说验尸结果
Bones, tell the professor what the autopsy revealed.
我们的船员因体内盐分耗尽而死
Our crewman died of salt depletion,
盐分突然间全没了
a sudden total loss of it.
任何医学标准都无法解释
Medically impossible by any standards.
而恰巧你们夫妇俩
And by coincidence, both you and Mrs. Crater
都需要盐片
requested salt tablets.
看来尊敬的医生还不知道我们需要它的原因
And your esteemed physician cannot explain our need for salt tablets?
我们都知道在这种炎热干燥的地方
We're all aware of the need for salt
必须补充盐分，教授
on a hot and arid planet like this, professor.
但目前的情况还是个谜，我不喜欢未解之谜
But it's a mystery, and I don't like mysteries.
问题看似简单，可却没这么简单
They give me a bellyache, and I got a beauty right now.
我们的盐开始有25磅
Nancy and I started with 25 pounds.
现在还剩这么多
This is what we have left.
这有什么好奇怪的呢？
Now, what is so mysterious about that?
是盐
Salt.
进取号的任务之一
One of the missions of the Enterprise
是保护人类在恶劣星球上的安全
is to protect human life in places like this.
我只有让你们撤回星舰
I'm gonna have to ask you and Mrs. Crater to stay aboard my ship
直到我们找出杀人真凶
until we find out what killed that crewman.
- 你无权这么做 - 我必须这么做，教授
- But you can't do that. - But I can, professor.
万万不可
You mustn't do it,
- 这会干扰我们的工作 - 何以见得？
- it'll interfere with our work. - How?
你们都呆了五年，少几天有何不同？
You've been here five years. Will a couple of days make a difference?
- 史波克 - 史波克在此
- Mr. Spock. - Spock here.
为教授和克瑞特夫人安排房间
Arrange quarters for Professor and Mrs. Crater.
植物分析结果如何？
Did you get the plant analysis?
是博尔吉亚的变种，舰长
It is the Borgia variety, captain.
不可能导致达内尔的死
Could not have caused Darnell's death.
吉姆，他开溜了
Jim, he's run off.
南茜！
Nancy!
你瞧！
You!
是盐！
Salt!
在我这儿，你闻啊
I've got salt. Smell it.
- 闻啊，南茜 - 克瑞特教授！
- Smell it, Nancy. - Professor Crater!
克瑞特教授
Professor Crater.
教授！
Professor!
- 教授 - 吉姆，吉姆
- Professor. - Jim. Jim.
是斯特尔贞
It's Sturgeon.
他死了
He's dead.
得把格林找到，格林！
We'd better locate Crewman Green. Green!
格林！
Green!
船员格林，答话！
Crewman Green, report!
格林！
Green!
船员格林，答话
Crewman Green, report.
格林
Green.
格林，你在哪？
Green, where are you?
克瑞特干的？他朝这走过
Could it be Crater? He came this way.
我不知道
I don't know.
格林！
Green!
- 你都看见了？ - 是的，长官
- Did you see this? - Yes, sir.
我发现他的时候，他已经死了
Sturgeon was dead when I found him.
当时我正在附近巡逻
I was circling to find whatever it was.
他脸上有相同的红圈
Same red rings on his face.
南茜呢？就是克瑞特夫人
Have you seen Nancy? Mrs. Crater?
没看到，长官，到处都找遍了
No, sir. I checked all through the ruins.
我很担心她，她不在房间，也不在挖掘区
I'm worried about her. She's not at the quarters, not at the diggings.
- 她可能出事了，南茜！ - 克瑞特！
- She could be in trouble. Nancy! - Crater!
南茜，我是伦纳德！
Nancy, it's Leonard!
- 我们得回星舰了 - 你们不能抛弃她
- We're beaming aboard the ship. - You can't leave her.
靠双腿不可能把这儿搜遍
We can't search this whole planet on foot.
得学学史波克，医生
Learn something from Mr. Spock, doctor.
理智地思考问题
Stop thinking with your glands.
进取号上的仪器
We have equipment aboard the Enterprise
可以侦测到这儿的一切身体热源
that could pinpoint a match lit anywhere on this planet
甚至燃烧的火柴棍
or the heat of a body.
传送室，我是寇克
Transporter Room, Kirk speaking.
三人准备登舰
Three to beam up.
- 寇克呼叫舰桥 - 我是史波克
- Kirk to bridge. - Spock here.
打开地面搜索装置
Break out the surface search equipment.
- 我需要两个人的坐标 - 收到
- I want coordinates on two people. - Acknowledged.
下面还有具尸体，是斯特尔贞
There's a body down there. Sturgeon.
我们会送他回家，长官
We'll bring him home, sir.
你需要休息，老骨头
You could use some sleep, Bones.
好的，吉姆
All right, Jim.
舰桥
Bridge.
哦，格林，那儿怎么了？
Oh, Green, what went on down there?
想得美！
Who do you think you are?
有些不对劲，舰长
Something odd, captain.
你说有两个人
You said two people.
教授和南茜·克瑞特
Professor and Nancy Crater.
可只找到一个人
We get a reading on only one person.
可能是克瑞特
Probably Crater.
他四处乱窜，像在找什么
He's circling, as if searching for something.
- 扩大搜索直径 - 是，长官
- Expand search radius. - Yes, sir.
别跟在我屁股后面
Why don't you go chase an asteroid.
嘿，贾尼丝，给我的吗？
Hey, Janice, is that for me?
门都没有
Don't you wish it was.
真是个辣妹
How about that?
是啊，他要是你的妞
Yeah, how'd you like to have her
该有多好
as your own personal yeoman?
苏鲁，你在哪？
Where are you, Sulu?
贾尼丝，我在这喂哀怨草
In here, feeding the weepers, Janice.
你的饭我端来了
Well, I've got your tray.
愿星河最美的鸟保佑你
May the great bird of the galaxy bless your planet.
谢谢
Thank you.
你好呀，博勒加德
Hello, Beauregard.
今天过得好吗，亲爱的？
How are you today, darling?
她叫格特鲁德
Her name's Gertrude.
才不是呢，他可是个“男生”哦
No, it's a he plant.
女人的直觉不会错的
A girl can tell.
为什么大家总喜欢叫无生命体为“她”？
Why do people have to call inanimate objects "she"?
像是“她是一艘快船”
Like, "She's a fast ship."
他才不是无生命体呢
He is not an inanimate object.
他可生动了，都让我觉得紧张
He's so animate, he makes me nervous.
实际上，我一直希望你的一株植物能抱紧我
In fact, I keep expecting one of these plants of yours to grab me.
你好，格林
Hello, Green.
他今天都不讲话的
He's not talking today.
你是喝蜥蜴酒还是怎么了？
You been nipping Saurian brandy or something?
没事，放轻松
Take it easy. Calm down.
太敏感了
Very sensitive.
他怎么神经兮兮的
He's the real spook.
以为自己在星际联欢还是怎么的？
Suppose he's going space-happy or something?
我房门打开时还是会咯咯作响
Hey, the door to my quarters still rattles when it opens.
能帮忙去看下吗？
Would you stop by and see if you can do something about it?
谢了，波比
Thanks, Bobby.
船员
Crewman...
我认识你吗？
...do I know you?
某种程度上认识，女士
In a way, ma'am.
你刚就想起，某个和我相像的人
You were just thinking of someone like me.
我随口说，但你看上去有些寂寞
I'm guessing, of course, but you do look a little lonely.
我明白了
I see.
所以，当我寂寞了我就想起你
So naturally, when I'm lonely I think of you.
你是斯瓦希里人？（东非的一个民族）
You're Swahili?
乌乎拉中尉请到舰桥来
Lieutenant Uhura to the bridge.
我最好把托盘带回去，拜，博勒加德
I better get this tray back. Bye, Beauregard.
等等，我和你一起去
Wait a minute. I'll walk along.
乌乎拉中尉请至舰桥报道
Lieutenant Uhura, report to the bridge.
乌乎拉中尉报道，马上来，长官
Lieutenant Uhura. On my way, sir.
麦考伊呼叫舰桥，舰长在吗？
McCoy to bridge. Captain there?
我在，没什么要报告的，医疗官
Kirk here. Nothing to report, doctor.
我们还没找到克瑞特夫人
We haven't located Mrs. Crater.
- 怎么了，睡不着吗？ - 没有
- what's the matter, can't you sleep? - Nope.
试试吃一片上周你给我的红色药丸
Try taking one of those red pills you gave me last week.
就能睡了
You'll sleep.
可以明确的现状是…
The simple fact is...
要么舰船的装备出现严重故障
...unless there's something seriously wrong with the ship's equipment,
要么方圆百里就只有一个人
there's only one person within a hundred-mile circle.
那好，我们去会会他
All right, we'll triangulate on him.
让克瑞特教授解释清楚他的妻子怎么了
We'll let Professor Crater explain what happened to his wife.
记好我的指令，中尉
Remember my instructions, lieutenant.
紧紧锁定我们
Keep a tight fix on us.
如果我们呼救，我希望在回音消失前
If we let out a yell, I want an armed party down there
- 就有武装队伍传送下来 - 明白，舰长
- before the echo dies. - Yes, captain.
（伦纳德·麦考伊，医疗官）
南茜
Nancy.
快，进来，进来
Well, come in, come in.
我一直很担心你
I've been worried sick about you.
怎么詹姆士没告诉我找到你了
I wonder why Jim didn't tell me he found you.
很高兴见到你，伦纳德
I'm so happy to see you, Leonard.
其他人，他们…嗯…
The others, they-- Well, I...
我和他们的关联不如和你之间的那么强烈
I don't relate to them as much as with you.
你对我的记忆如此深刻
You have such strong memories of me.
- 呃，我… - 你在乎我，不是吗，伦纳德？
- Well, I... - You do care, don't you, Leonard?
这让我感觉…
It makes me feel so...
非常安全
So safe.
南茜…
Nancy...
顾虑我丈夫？
My husband?
我更喜欢你的情感
I like your feelings better.
更加…
Much...
强烈…
...stronger.
但是你累了
But you're tired.
你需要休息
You need to rest.
你和詹姆士·寇克一样坏
You're as bad as Jim Kirk.
他叮嘱我吃这个
He's been telling me to take these.
嗯，我想你应该吃
Well, I think you should.
我给你倒点水
I'll get you some water.
看他的脸！
Look at his face!
舰桥，我是苏鲁，9号甲板第2区有状况
Bridge, Sulu. Trouble on Deck 9, Section 2.
我们需要医疗队
We need a medical team.
舰长日志，星历1513.8
Captain's log, stardate 1513.8.
此刻我确信船员的横死
I am now certain that the violent death of my crewman
是由某种奇怪生命体导致的
was caused by some strange life form.
我非常担心
I was so worried.
你丈夫举止奇怪
Your husband acting strange.
船员不断死去
Crewmen dying.
你太累了，亲爱的，睡吧
You're so tired, darling. Just rest now.
医务部门警报
Medical Department alert.
医生和医护人员请确认
Doctors and medics, acknowledge.
没事，亲爱的，没什么事
It's nothing, dear. It's nothing.
好好睡吧
You just sleep.
南茜会处理好所有的事
Nancy will take care of everything.
麦考伊医疗官请到舰桥报道
Dr. McCoy to the bridge.
舰长日志，补充
Captain's log, additional.
强健以及武装的船员
Armed and able-bodied crewmen
不易被攻击、杀害
are not attacked and slaughtered this easily.
显然，凶手靠近时能够瘫痪他们
Apparently, the killer can immobilize them as it approaches,
也许是拥有催眠或麻痹的能力
perhaps with some hypnotic or paralyzing power.
答案就在克瑞特教授身上
The answer lies with Professor Crater.
克瑞特教授？
Professor Crater?
- 走开，我们不想看到你 - 我们？
- Go away, we don't want you here. - We?
教授，您的妻子在哪？我们很担心她
Where's your wife, professor? We're concerned about her.
我有武器，走开
I'm armed. Go away.
您妻子在哪，教授？
Where's your wife, professor?
这不关你们的事
She's no concern of yours.
我们很担心她的安危，你不也是吗？
We're worried about her safety. Aren't you?
教授，您是个明理的人，让我…
Professor, you're a reasonable man. Let me--
- 我是寇克 - 舰长，伤亡报告
- Kirk here. - Casualty, captain.
巴哈特被发现死于9号甲板，症状一样
Barnhart was found dead on Deck 9. Same symptoms.
史波克插入，舰长，这里有情况
Spock cutting in, captain. Something here,
穿过你左边的拱桥
through the arches to your left.
待命，苏鲁，史波克有情况
Stand by, Mr. Sulu. Spock has something.
格林
Green.
- 他和我们一起传送回舰船了啊 - 或者是别的什么东西
- He beamed up to the ship with us. - Or something did.
进取号，寇克呼叫
Enterprise, from Kirk.
舰桥，苏鲁
Bridge, Sulu.
有入侵者登入舰船
You have an intruder aboard.
可能伪装成了船员格林
Could be masquerading as Crewman Green.
战备部署，启动安全等级3
General Quarters, Security Condition 3.
战备部署，安全等级3，长官
G.Q., Security 3, sir.
3级战备部署，入侵警报
General Quarters 3. Intruder alert.
G.Q. 3. Intruder alert.
3级战备部署，入侵警报
General Quarters 3, intruder alert.
G.Q. 3, intruder alert.
已开始3级战备部署，舰长
Reporting G.Q. 3 secure, captain.
你们是否需要援助？
Do you require assistance there?
克瑞特知道那生物，如果我们能生擒他…
Crater knows the creature. If we can take him alive...
不需要，中尉
Negative, lieutenant.
但继续锁定我们
But keep locked in on us.
完毕，现在去解决他吧
Kirk out. Let's get him.
我们不想见到你们
We don't want you here.
我们在这里很开心
We're happy alone.
为此我可以杀死你们
I'll kill to stay alone.
听到了吗，寇克？
You hear that, Kirk?
要么你杀了我，我不在乎
Or you'll have to kill me. I don't care either way.
显然，生擒他有点难度
Obviously, taking him alive is going to be difficult.
把你的相位枪设定为1/4档，我设定成击晕模式
Set your phaser on one-quarter. I'll leave mine on stun.
为何要拿你的命为他冒险？
Why risk your life for his?
他没想杀我们，只是想吓唬我们
He's not trying to kill us, he's trying to frighten us.
而且成功的吓唬到我们了
And he's doing a pretty good job.
3级战备部署已完成，除5、7、10号甲板
G.Q. 3 now secured, except for Decks 5, 7 and 10.
请报告情况
Come in, please.
苏鲁，他不在补给室和维修室
He's not in Supply and Maintenance, Sulu.
收到，乌乎拉，现在确认工程甲板
All right, Uhura. Engineering Deck now.
浏览那里的船员图像
Run through file photos of the crewmen there.
- 检查中 - 5号甲板报告
- Check. - Deck 5 reporting.
船员格林不在房间，没人见到他
Crewman Green is not in his quarters. No one has seen him.
找到他时保持警惕，他不是真正的格林
Keep in mind if you find him, he's not Crewman Green.
舰长说格林已经死了
Captain reports Green's dead.
而且他，或者应该是它跟踪过我
And he-- Or rather, it followed me.
我还以为有什么事让它神经紧张
I thought there was something twitchy about him.
不管是他还是什么，也许也是你见到的那个，中尉
He, or whatever, was probably your crewman too, lieutenant.
一定是它
He must have been it.
知道吗，要有这样的船员我一定有印象
You know, I would have remembered a crewman like him.
那生物让你有的找了，苏鲁先生？
The creature leading you a merry chase, Mr. Sulu?
生物？
Creature?
或者说是杀死船员的东西
Or whatever it is that's killing the crewmen.
没准我能帮上忙
Perhaps I can help.
把详情告诉我
Fill me in.
- 好了 - 确认
- Set. - Acknowledged.
克瑞特
Crater.
你的妻子在哪？
Your wife, professor, where is she?
教授，你的妻子在哪？
她…
She...
是她们种族仅存的
...was the last of her kind.
她们种族仅存的？
The last of her kind?
它们种族的最后一个
The last of its kind.
地球的历史，还记得吗？
Earth history, remember?
就像是候鸽或者野牛
Like the passenger pigeon or the buffalo.
我感觉怪怪的
I feel strange.
只是眩晕，很快就能思考了
You're just stunned. You'll be able to think in a minute.
地球野牛，怎么样了？
The Earth buffalo, what about it?
曾经数百万的野牛，草原上乌压一片
Once there were millions of them. Prairies black with them.
一个族群就能占领3个州
One herd covered three whole states,
移动时，就跟打雷一样
and when they moved, they were like thunder.
现在它们灭绝了，你想说这个？
And now they're gone. Is that what you mean?
就像这里的生物一样
Like the creatures here.
曾经有着数百万的它们
Once there were millions of them.
现在只剩一个
Now there's one left.
南茜明白
Nancy understood.
一直用过去时态
Always in the past tense.
你的妻子在哪，她现在人呢？
Where's your wife? Where is she now?
死了，埋在小山上，它杀死了她
Dead. Buried up on the hill. It killed her.
- 什么时候？ - 噢，一年…
- When? - Oh, a year...
还是两年前？
Or was it two?
寇克呼叫进取号
Kirk to Enterprise.
舰桥呼叫舰长，我是苏鲁
Bridge to captain. sulu here.
苏鲁，可以肯定的是，入侵者能伪装成任何人
It's definite, Mr. Sulu. The intruder can assume any shape,
船员，你，我，任何人，明白？
a crewman, you, myself, anyone. Understand?
收到，舰长
Affirmative, captain.
升级到4级战备部署
Go to G.Q. 4.
4级战备部署，舰长
General Quarters 4, captain.
这生物只不过是想活下来，这是它的权力，不是吗？
The creature was trying to survive. It has that right, doesn't it?
寇克呼叫传送室，三人等待传送
Kirk to Transporter Room, three to beam up.
他们生存需要盐，但是没有盐了
They needed salt to stay alive. There was no more salt.
它是最后一个了
It's the last one.
和灭绝的野牛没有区别
The buffalo. There is no difference.
有一个区别，教授，你的生物正在杀害我的船员
There's one, professor. Your creature is killing my people.
舰长日志，续
Captain's log, continuing.
进取号被某种生物入侵
The Enterprise has been invaded by a creature
该生物不仅能随意变形而且具备麻痹…
capable of assuming any form and with the capacity to paralyze
并杀害我们任意一人的能力
and draw the life from any one of us.
5号甲板，第三区
Deck 5, Section 3,
5号甲板，第三区，报告
Deck 5, section 3, report.
这是3-A警卫，3-B在视野内
Security 3-A here, 3-B in sight.
不是，舰长，我检查了舰船上所有的成员
Negative, captain. I've checked every face on this vessel.
没有我见过的那个
It was not a crewman I saw.
文书员兰德，那个格林跟你在一起多久？
Yeoman Rand, how long was this Green with you?
久到他…
As long as he--
它确定拿不到我托盘上的盐，长官
It thought it could get to the salt on my tray, sir.
史波克？
Mr. Spock?
已在所有甲板和工程舱层
Supplies of salt have been set out as bait
放了盐做诱饵，舰长
at all decks and engineering levels, captain.
但至今却没有任何人或生物靠近
However, no one or nothing has approached them as yet.
麦考伊医生？
Dr. McCoy?
什么事？
Yes?
医疗部的报告，医生
The Medical Department report, doctor.
哦，我们可以把盐直接给它而没必要设下陷阱
Well, we could offer it salt without tricks.
它没有主动袭击我们的理由
There's no reason for it to attack us.
你的想法值得赞扬，医生，但这理由太草率了
Your attitude is laudable, doctor, but your reasoning is reckless.
这种生物在摄食之后毫无威胁
The creature is not dangerous when fed.
不，它仅仅是为了生存
No, it's simply trying to survive
通过与生俱来的能力幻化成他人的模样
by using its natural ability to take other forms.
就像变色龙
The way the chameleon uses
使用它的保护色，这能力无疑…
its protective colouring. An ability retained, no doubt,
是从祖先那遗传而来的
from its primitive state,
就像我们人类由过去的尖牙进化到切牙
the way we have retained our incisor teeth. They were once fangs.
某些部位的肌肉是为了打猎而生长的
Certain of our muscles were designed for chase.
它们就像我们人类要使用牙齿和肌肉才能存活下来那样
It uses its ability the way we would use our muscles and teeth if necessary
使用它的能力
to stay alive.
并且和我们一样，也是某种智能生物
And like us, it's an intelligent animal.
所以…我们没有必要追杀它
It's-- There's no need to hunt it down.
很有意思的假设，医生
A very interesting hypothesis, doctor.
- 简报室 - 已封锁全部过道
- Briefing Room. - All the halls sealed off.
所有武器清点完毕并被封存
All weapons accounted for and locked away.
所有舰层的四级安全系统已生效
Security 4 in effect on every level.
目前还没有入侵者的线索
Still no lead on the intruder.
好的，中尉，继续搜索
Thank you, lieutenant. Continue the search.
克瑞特，我们对这种生物一无所知
Crater, we don't know who or what we're looking for.
我们现在急需你的帮助
We need your help, and now.
我强烈要求，甚至祈求你们离开我的星球
I demanded, I even begged that you get off my planet.
当你看到它的时候能辨别出它吗？
Can you recognise this thing when you see it?
教授…
Professor...
如果你肯协助我们，我们将放弃对你的指控
...I'll forego charges up to this point,
但这生物已经入侵到我的星舰，我得抓住它
but this creature is aboard my ship, and I'll have it,
否则我把它连你一起逮捕，现在告诉我，它在哪？
or I'll have your skin or both. Now, where is it?
我深爱着南茜
I loved Nancy very much.
很少有女人像她那般迷人
Few women like my Nancy.
她活在我的梦里
She lives in my dreams.
她哼着歌谣在我的梦中漫步
She walks and sings in my dreams.
然后为了你它幻化成了南茜
And it becomes Nancy for you.
它并不是为了欺骗我，它也没有欺骗我，它需要爱
Not because of tricks. It doesn't trick me. It needs love
就像它需要盐
as much as it needs salt.
当它杀死了南茜，我也几乎杀死了它，可是…
When it killed Nancy, I almost destroyed it, but...
它不止是单纯的野兽
...it isn't just a beast.
它是一种智能生物，它也是它们仅存的了
It is intelligent and the last of its kind.
你太同情它们了，克瑞特
You bleed too much, Crater.
你真的是非常的纯洁和高尚
You're too pure and noble.
你是真的拯救了它
Are you saving the last of its kind,
还是说你把这星球当做…
or has this become Crater's private heaven,
你为所欲为的地方？
here on this planet?
那玩意变成了你的妻子，爱人，好友，圣人
This thing becomes wife, lover, best friend, wise man,
愚人，偶像，奴隶
fool, idol, slave.
这样的日子并不糟糕
It isn't a bad life
让世间万物都听你的使唤
to have everyone in the universe at your beck and call,
然后你赢得了一切
and you win all the arguments.
你不会明白的
You don't understand.
无论这东西变成什么你都能认出来吗？
Have you learned to see this thing in whatever form it becomes?
- 是的 - 你打算协助我们了吗？
- Yes. - Are you gonna help us find it?
抱歉，我做不到
Sorry, I can't.
我建议使用“吐真剂”，长官
Recommend we use truth serum, captain.
医生？
Doctor?
好吧，我不建议使用它，不过事到如今
Well, I resist using it, but in this case,
教授或许会给我们真相
the professor will give us the truth.
把他带走
Take him.
我和你一同去，医生
I'll accompany you, doctor.
好的，当然可以
Oh, yes, of course.
寇克舰长请到医务室
Captain Kirk to Dispensary.
寇克舰长请到医务室，紧急情况
Captain Kirk to Dispensary. Urgent.
那不是麦考伊
It wasn't McCoy.
是那生物变的，它攻击了我
It was the creature. It hit me.
克瑞特抢走了我的相位器
Crater grabbed my phaser.
当时我感到麦考伊有些奇怪，顿时心生疑惑
I wondered about McCoy. A doubt had crossed my mind.
长官
Captain.
- 克瑞特教授 - 死了
- Professor Crater. - Dead.
但它也抓住了你
But it had you too.
幸运的是，我们的祖先起源于一片和你们不同的海洋
Fortunately, my ancestors spawned in another ocean than yours did.
我血液中的盐分和你们有很大的不同
My blood salts are quite different.
伦纳德，伦纳德，求你了，快醒醒！
Leonard. Leonard, wake up, please!
帮帮我，帮帮我，伦纳德
Help me. Help me, Leonard.
他们想杀了我，快阻止他们！
They're trying to kill me. Don't let them kill me!
是谁？别慌，别慌，这里没人会伤害你
Who? Easy, easy, nobody's going to hurt you.
但你必须得帮我！
But you must help me!
让开，老骨头
Move aside, Bones.
- 发生了什么，吉姆？ - 那不是南茜，老骨头
- What's going on here, Jim? - She's not Nancy, Bones.
你疯了吗？
Are you insane?
它杀害了四名船员，刚杀了克瑞特
It killed four crewmen, now Crater.
- 它？ - 是那生物，它杀人
- It? - The creature. It kills.
它需要盐分来维持生命
It needs salt to live.
- 老骨头，快让开 - 不！
- Bones, move aside. - No!
我猜它还想要更多
My guess is she needs more.
想要吗，南茜？
You want it, Nancy?
过来拿吧
Come and get it.
你在恐吓她，吉姆
You're frightening her, Jim.
不是在恐吓，看看她，她饿了
Not fright. Hunger. Look at her.
伦纳德，如果你还爱我，就把他赶走
Leonard, if you love me, make him go away.
快过来，你想要这些对吗，南茜？
Come on. Do you want this, Nancy?
快啊，南茜，快来拿啊，就在这里
Come on, Nancy. Come and get it. Here it is.
- 快帮帮我 - 我开不了枪，快走开
- Help me. - I can't fire. Out of the way.
- 快住手，吉姆！ - 麦考伊，快走开！
- Stop it, Jim! - McCoy, out of the way!
你到底是怎么了，脑子坏了吗？
What's the matter with you? Are you out of your mind?
快让开
Get out of the way.
他会杀了舰长
It's killing the captain.
- 快开枪，医生，快 - 不
- Shoot it, doctor, quickly. - No.
不！
No!
舰长就快没命了，快开枪
It's killing the captain. Shoot, quick!
我不会朝南茜开枪
I won't shoot Nancy.
这不是南茜
This is not Nancy.
如果她真的是南茜，她受的了这个吗？
If she were Nancy, could she take this?
停下，快停下，史波克！
Stop it! Stop it, Spock!
快停下！
Stop it!
那是南茜吗，医生？
Is that Nancy, doctor?
不
No.
伦纳德，伦纳德，不
Leonard. Leonard, no.
伦纳德，求你了
Leonard, please.
上帝，请宽恕我
Lord, forgive me.
我很遗憾，老骨头
I'm sorry, Bones.
准备脱离环绕轨道，舰长
Ready to leave orbit, captain.
有什么问题吗，舰长？
Is something wrong, captain?
我刚在思考野牛，史波克
I was thinking about the buffalo, Mr. Spock.
1级曲速，苏鲁先生
Warp 1, Mr. Sulu.
1级曲速，长官，开始脱离轨道
Warp 1, sir. Leaving orbit.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏